Homer Shantz Photograph Collection, 1904-1962 (bulk 1911-1958)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Homer Shantz Photograph Collection 1904-1962(bulk 1911-1958)
MS 481
Shantz, H. L.(Homer LeRoy),1876-1958
The Homer Shantz photograph collection is composed of glass plates, photographs, and negatives documenting distinct environments around the world. The collection was created by University of Arizona president and botanist Homer Shantz. Images from the 1919-1920 Smithsonian African Expedition and the 1913 International Phytogeography Expedition are featured in this collection. The collection also contains negatives and prints by Jack McCormick and Walter S. Phillips.
20 linear feet (approximately 16,000 negatives and prints; 149 glass plates)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restirctions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Homer LeRoy Shantz was born on January 24 1876 in Kent County, Michigan. In 1901 he received his Bachelor of Science in botany from Colorado College. After graduation he remained at Colorado College where he taught botany and zoology until 1903. He received his PHD from the University of Nebraska in 1905 and proceeded to teach at the University of Missouri and Louisiana State University. Beginning in 1908, Shantz worked for the Bureau of Plant Industry under the United States Department of Agriculture were he published “Natural Vegetation as an Indicator of the Capabilities of Land for Crop Production in the Great Plains Area” among others.
He was a member of the 1919-1920 Smithsonian- Universal Film Manufacturing Company Expedition also known as the Smithsonian African Expedition. This expedition began on July 16, 1919 and ended July 14, 1920. Its mission was to collect specimens of plants and animals from the interior of Africa and South Africa. Shantz role was to survey plant resources and to create a vegetation map of the surveyed area. In total Shantz produced over 3,500 photographs that detail plant and vegetation in Africa. In 1923 he published The Vegetation Soils of Africa with C.F. Marbut. He returned to Africa in 1924 and 1956-1957.
In 1928, Shantz became the 10th president of The University of Arizona. During his tenure at the University the College of Law was accredited and the College of Fine Arts, School of Music, School Business and Public Administration, and the College of Liberal of Arts were established. He was a monumental figure in the creation of the Saguaro National Monument, and in creating the vegetation areas that are found around the University. He resigned from the presidency in 1936.
Shantz became the first director of the United States Forest Division of Wildlife Management in 1936, he served in until 1944. In 1956 he traveled one more time to Africa as a member of the Geography Branch of the Office of Naval Research. In this trip he re-photographed many of the sites he had documented earlier. In 1958 he published Photographic Documentation of Vegetational Changes in Africa Over a Third of a Century, which culminated his work in Africa. Homer Shantz died in Rapid City, South Dakota, on June 23, 1958.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 8 series
Series I: Index
Series II: Indexed images
Series III: Non-indexed Shantz photographs
Series IV: Jack McCormick
Series V: Walter S. Phillips
Subseries 1: Locations
Subseries 2: Maps
Subseries 3: Microscopic Slides
Subseries 4: Plants
Subseries 5: Specimens
Subseries 6: Various Images
Series VI: Unidentified Photographers
Subseries 1: Agave Species
Subseries 2: Plants
Subseries 3: Specimens
Subseries 4: Various Locations
Series VII: Card Catalog
Series VIII: Oversize Materials
Subseries 1: Environmental compare
Subseries 2: Walter Phillips oversize materials
Subseries 3: Identified Landscapes
Subseries 4: Various prints
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains images by Homer Shantz, Walter Phillips, Jack McCormick and unknown photographers. The bulk of the images document Shantz work from 1907-1959 and can be searched using the index that accompanied the collection. The collection contains images that document environmental change in the United States, Africa, Switzerland, and Mexico. It also contains images of plant specimens and photographs of plants taken through a microscope. The format of the collection is primarily 3x5 negatives.
Access Terms
Phillips, Walter S. (Walter Sargeant), 1905-1975
McCormick, Jack
Phytogeography
Saguaro National Park (Ariz.)
Botany—Africa
Botany—United States
Glass Negatives
Container List
- Index, 1904-1957, Series I:
  This series contains the Index for the negatives in the year 1904-1957. Years 1923 and 1924 were compiled at the time the collection was processed.
  - Index, 1904-1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Index, 1914-1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Index, 1919-1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Index, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Index, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Index, 1927-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series II: Indexed Images
  This series contains negatives, prints, and glass plates. It is organized in order according to the Index. The glass plates for years 1904 to 1911 can be found in boxes 3 to 11. Box 12 to Box 62 contain 4x5 negatives and prints.
  - 1904A to 1904-12, 15; 4x5 inches glass plates (Box 3)
  - 1905-108 to 1905-1, 7; 4x5 inches glass plates (Box 4)
  - 1907 to 6/11/07, 22; 4x5 inches glass plates (Box 5)
  - 1907-28 to 1907-58, 19; 4x5 inches glass plates (Box 6)
  - 1907-59 to 1907-98, 15; 4x5 inches glass plates (Box 7)
  - 1907-147 to 1907-120, 19; 4x5 inches glass plates (Box 8)
  - 1907-121 to 11-27-1907, 10; 4x5 inches glass plates (Box 9)
  - 5-2-1908 to 9-1-1908, 24; 4x5 inches glass plates (Box 10)
  - 9-1-1908 to 9-13-1908, 17; 4x5 inches glass plates (Box 11)
  - 1907 to O-5-1909 (Box 12)
  - O-6-1909 to S-12-1910 (Box 13)
  - T-1-1910 to g-12-1911 (Box 14)
  - h-1-1911 to f-12-1912 (Box 15)
  - A-5-1913 to CC-12-1913 (Box 16)
  - DD-1-1913 to E-4-1914 (Box 17)
  - E-6-1914 to F-12-1914 (Box 18)
  - g-4-1914 to Y-5-1915 (Box 19)
  - Y-6-1915 to cc-15-1915 (Box 20)
  - A-9-1916 to FF-12-1916 (Box 21)
  - GG-1-1916 to r-5-1916 (Box 22)
  - r-6-1916 to W-5-1917 (Box 23)
  - W-6-1917 to C-5-1918 (Box 24)
  - C-6-1918 to 36090 (Box 25)
  - 36091 to 36365 (Box 26)
  - 36366 to 36680 (Box 27)
  - 36681 to 36960 (Box 28)
  - 36961 to 37185 (Box 29)
  - 37186 to 37410 (Box 30)
  - 37411 to 37640 (Box 31)
  - 37641 to 37914 (Box 32)
  - 37915 to 38185 (Box 33)
  - 38186 to 38445 (Box 34)
  - 38446 to 38660 (Box 35)
  - 38661 to 38884 (Box 36)
  - 38885 to 39085 (Box 37)
  - 39086 to 39300 (Box 38)
  - 39301 to 39545 (Box 39)
  - 39540 to F-12-1922 (Box 40)
  - G-1-1922 to a-5-1923 (Box 41)
  - a-6-1923 to O-12-1924 (Box 42)
  - P-1-1924 to p-12-1924 (Box 43)
  - q-1-1924 to T¹-12-1924 (Box 44)
  - U¹-1-1924 to I-12-1925 (Box 45)
  - J-1-1925 to C-12-1926 (Box 46)
  - D-1-1926 to H-4-1927 (Box 47)
  - H-5-1927 to DD-1-1927 (Box 48)
  - DD-2-1927 to E-5-1930 (Box 49)
  - E-6-1930 to B-3-1931 (Box 50)
  - B-5-1931 to X-11-1931 (Box 51)
  - Y-1-1931 to W-4-1932 (Box 52)
  - W-5-1932 to L-5-1933 (Box 53)
  - L-6-1933 to F-9-1935 (Box 54)
  - F-10-1935 to H-12-1937 (Box 55)
  - I-1-1937 to M-12-1938 (Box 56)
  - N-1-1938 to K-7-1941 (Box 57)
  - K-8-1941 to Y-3-1949 (Box 58)
  - Y-5-1949 to G-11-1956 (Box 59)
  - G-12-1956 to J-4-1957 (Box 60)
  - J-5-1957 to B¹-12-1957 (Box 61)
  - A-7-1958 to J-12-1958 (Box 62)
- Series III: Non-index Shantz photographs
  This series contains negatives and prints that were not identified in the index. It is organized alphabetically by subject.
  - Canada, Lake Moraine (Box 62, Tab 1)
  - Cars (Box 62, Tab 2)
  - Colorado, Aroyo (Box 62, Tab 3)
  - Colorado, Beecher Island (Box 62, Tab 4)
  - Colorado, Black Forest (Box 62, Tab 5)
  - Colorado, Clifford (Box 62, Tab 6)
  - Colorado, Colorado Springs (Box 62, Tab 7)
  - Colorado, Eastonville (Box 62, Tab 8)
  - Colorado, First View (Box 62, Tab 9)
  - Colorado, Freemont Butte (Box 62, Tab 10)
  - Colorado, La Junta (Box 62, Tab 11)
  - Colorado, Lamar (Box 62, Tab 12)
  - Colorado, Las Animas (Box 62, Tab 13)
  - Colorado, Limon (Box 62, Tab 14)
  - Colorado, Palmer Lake (Box 62, Tab 15)
  - Colorado, Piñon (Box 62, Tab 16)
  - Colorado, Seven Lakes (Box 62, Tab 17)
  - Colorado, Sheridan Lake (Box 62, Tab 18)
  - Colorado, Vernon (Box 62, Tab 19)
  - Colorado, Wray (Box 62, Tab 20)
  - Colorado, Yuma (Box 62, Tab 21)
  - Excursion group prints (Box 63, Tab 1)
  - Excursion members conducting fieldwork (Box 63, Tab 2)
  - Fairy rings (Box 63, Tab 3)
  - International Phytogeographical Excursion (Box 63, Tab 4)
  - Mesa terrains (Box 63, Tab 5)
  - Mitchells Ranch (Box 63, Tab 6)
  - Nebraska, North Plate (Box 63, Tab 7)
  - Shantz conducting fieldwork (Box 63, Tab 8)
  - Panoramas (Box 63, Tab 9)
- Series IV: Jack McCormick
  This series contains negatives and photographs identified as being created by Jack McCormick. The series is organized alphabetically by subject matter.
  - Aerial views (Box 63, Tab 10)
  - Animals (Box 63, Tab 11)
  - Arizona, Fort Bowie (Box 63, Tab 12)
  - Black Canyon of Gunnison National Park (Box 63, Tab 13)
  - Cactus (Box 63, Tab 14)
  - Candy (Box 63, Tab 15)
  - Cars (Box 63, Tab 16)
  - Coke a Cola (Box 63, Tab 17)
  - Deserts (Box 63, Tab 18)
  - Disaster scenes (Box 63, Tab 19)
  - Farms (Box 63, Tab 20)
  - Farm fields (Box 63, Tab 21)
  - Forests (Box 63, Tab 22)
  - Grasslands (Box 63, Tab 23)
  - Labs (Box 63, Tab 24)
  - Lake (Box 63, Tab 25)
  - New Mexico, White Sands (Box 63, Tab 26)
  - Portraits (Box 63, Tab 27)
  - Plains (Box 63, Tab 28)
  - Rocks (Box 63, Tab 29)
  - Roots (Box 63, Tab 30)
  - Ruins (Box 63, Tab 31)
  - Signs (Box 63, Tab 32)
  - Students conducting fieldwork in deserts (Box 63, Tab 33)
  - Students conducting fieldwork in forests (Box 63, Tab 34)
  - Terrains (Box 63, Tab 35)
  - Trees (Box 63, Tab 36)
- Series V: Walter S. Phillips, ca. 1950-1960s
  This series contains photographs and negatives accredited to Walter S. Phillips. It is divided into six subseries and is organized in alphabetical order.
  - Subseries 1: Locations
    - Arizona, Ajo (Box 64, Tab 1)
    - Arizona, Apache County (Box 64, Tab 2)
    - Arizona, Bagdad (Box 64, Tab 3)
    - Arizona, Boboquivari Peak Wilderness (Box 64, Tab 4)
    - Arizona, Benson (Box 64, Tab 5)
    - Arizona, Cameron (Box 64, Tab 6)
    - Arizona, Casa Grande (Box 64, Tab 7)
    - Arizona, Cave Creek (Box 64, Tab 8)
    - Arizona, Cedar Ridge (Box 64, Tab 9)
    - Arizona, Chiricahua Mountains (Box 64, Tab 10)
    - Arizona, Cochise County (Box 64, Tab 11)
    - Arizona, Coconino County (Box 64, Tab 12)
    - Arizona, Flagstaff (Box 64, Tab 13)
    - Arizona, Fort Apache (Box 64, Tab 14)
    - Arizona, Foxboro Lake (Box 64, Tab 15)
    - Arizona, Gila County (Box 64, Tab 16)
    - Arizona, Grand Canyon (Box 64, Tab 17)
    - Arizona, Kitt Peak (Box 64, Tab 18)
    - Arizona, Kofa Mountains (Box 64, Tab 19)
    - Arizona, Little Colorado River (Box 64, Tab 20)
    - Arizona, Lukachukai Mountains (Box 64, Tab 21)
    - Arizona, McNary (Box 64, Tab 22)
    - Arizona, Mogollom Rim (Box 64, Tab 23)
    - Arizona, Navaho County (Box 65, Tab 1)
    - Arizona, Oak Creek Canyon (Box 65, Tab 2)
    - Arizona, Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument (Box 65, Tab 3)
    - Arizona, Patagonia (Box 65, Tab 4)
    - Arizona, Patato Lake (Box 65, Tab 5)
    - Arizona, Peach Springs (Box 65, Tab 6)
    - Arizona, Peeples Valley (Box 65, Tab 7)
    - Arizona, Phoenix (Box 65, Tab 8)
    - Arizona, Pima County (Box 65, Tab 9)
    - Arizona, Presumido Pass (Box 65, Tab 10)
    - Arizona, Ramsey Canyon (Box 65, Tab 11)
    - Arizona, Sacaton (Box 65, Tab 12)
    - Arizona, Safford (Box 65, Tab 13)
    - Arizona, Saguaro National Park (Box 65, Tab 14)
    - Arizona, San Xavier Mission (Box 65, Tab 15)
    - Arizona, Santa Cruz Valley (Box 65, Tab 16)
    - Arizona, Sells (Box 65, Tab 17)
    - Arizona, Sonoita Creek (Box 65, Tab 18)
    - Arizona, Tinajas Altas Mountains (Box 65, Tab 19)
    - Arizona, Tonalea (Box 65, Tab 20)
    - Arizona, Tonto Basin (Box 65, Tab 21)
    - Arizona, Tuba City (Box 65, Tab 22)
    - Arizona, Tucson (Box 65, Tab 23)
    - Arizona, University of Arizona (Box 66, Tab 1)
    - Arizona, White Mountains (Box 66, Tab 2)
    - Arizona, Williams (Box 66, Tab 3)
    - Arizona, Wikenburg (Box 66, Tab 4)
    - Australia, plague of Cactoblastis Catorum (Box 66, Tab 5)
    - California, Avenue of the Giants (Box 66, Tab 6)
    - California, Magma (Box 66, Tab 7)
    - California, Mt. Whitney (Box 67, Tab 1)
    - California, Palm Springs- Palm Canyon (Box 67, Tab 2)
    - Canada, Ontario-Petewawa Forest (Box 67, Tab 3)
    - Colorado, Riffle (Box 67, Tab 4)
    - Colorado, Rocky Mountain National Park (Box 67, Tab 5)
    - Colorado, Sharlow Mountains Lake Reservoir (Box 67, Tab 6)
    - Connecticut, Connecticut River (Box 67, Tab 7)
    - Death Valley National Park (Box 67, Tab 8)
    - Four Corners (Box 67, Tab 9)
    - Montana, Fairview (Box 67, Tab 10)
    - Montana, Forsyth (Box 67, Tab 11)
    - Montana, Gardiner (Box 67, Tab 12)
    - Montana, Havre (Box 67, Tab 13)
    - Montana, Hebgen Lake (Box 67, Tab 14)
    - Montana, Lewistown (Box 67, Tab 15)
    - Montana, Lombard (Box 67, Tab 16)
    - Montana, Moccasin (Box 67, Tab 17)
    - Montana, Roundup (Box 67, Tab 18)
    - Montana, Townsend (Box 67, Tab 19)
    - Nebraska, Crawford (Box 67, Tab 20)
    - Nebraska, Sidney (Box 67, Tab 21)
    - Nevada, Red Rock Canyon (Box 67, Tab 22)
    - Nevada, Sequoia National Park (Box 67, Tab 23)
    - New Hampshire, Meriden (Box 67, Tab 24)
    - New Mexico, Cienega Ranch (Box 67, Tab 25)
    - North Carolina, Smoky Mountains-Lake Fortuna (Box 67, Tab 26)
    - North Dakota, Fort Lincoln (Box 67, Tab 27)
    - North Dakota, Fryburg (Box 67, Tab 28)
    - North Dakota, Hettinger (Box 67, Tab 29)
    - North Dakota, Mandan (Box 67, Tab 30)
    - North Dakota, Medora (Box 67, Tab 31)
    - Oregon, Brooking (Box 67, Tab 32)
    - Oregon, Crater Lake (Box 67, Tab 33)
    - Sonora, Guaymas (Box 67, Tab 34)
    - Sonora, Magdalena (Box 67, Tab 35)
    - South Dakota, Arpan (Box 67, Tab 36)
    - South Dakota, Belle Fourche (Box 67, Tab 37)
    - South Dakota, Highmore (Box 67, Tab 38)
    - South Dakota, Hot Springs (Box 67, Tab 39)
    - South Dakota, Kadoka (Box 67, Tab 40)
    - South Dakota, Mt. Rushmore (Box 67, Tab 41)
    - South Dakota, Newell (Box 67, Tab 42)
    - South Dakota, Pine Ridge (Box 67, Tab 43)
    - South Dakota, Rumford (Box 67, Tab 44)
    - South Dakota, Spearfish (Box 67, Tab 45)
    - South Dakota, Timberlake (Box 67, Tab 46)
    - South Dakota, Whitewood (Box 67, Tab 47)
    - Texas, El Paso (Box 67, Tab 48)
    - Unidentified Locations (Box 67, Tab 49)
    - Utah, Bluff (Box 68, Tab 1)
    - Utah, Bryce Canyon (Box 68, Tab 2)
    - Utah, Chinle Creek (Box 68, Tab 3)
    - Utah, La Sol Mountains (Box 68, Tab 4)
    - Utah, Mexican Hat (Box 68, Tab 5)
    - Utah, Salahkai Mesa (Box 68, Tab 6)
    - Utah, San Juan River (Box 68, Tab 7)
    - Wyoming, Buffalo (Box 68, Tab 8)
    - Wyoming, Casper (Box 68, Tab 9)
    - Wyoming, Cody (Box 68, Tab 10)
    - Wyoming, Crazy Woman Creek (Box 68, Tab 11)
    - Wyoming, Devils Tower (Box 68, Tab 12)
    - Wyoming, Frannie (Box 68, Tab 13)
    - Wyoming, Grand Teton National Park (Box 68, Tab 14)
    - Wyoming, Hullet (Box 68, Tab 15)
    - Wyoming, Story (Box 68, Tab 16)
    - Wyoming, Sundance (Box 68, Tab 17)
    - Yellowstone National Park (Box 68, Tab 18)
  - Subseries 2: Maps
    - Arizona (Box 68, Tab 19)
    - Australia (Box 68, Tab 20)
    - Colorado (Box 68, Tab 21)
    - Colorado River Delta (Box 68, Tab 22)
    - Navaho Nation (Box 68, Tab 23)
    - North America (Box 68, Tab 24)
    - Penacate Region (Box 68, Tab 25)
    - United States (Box 68, Tab 26)
    - Utah (Box 68, Tab 27)
  - Subseries 3: Microscopic Slides
    - Acer (Box 68, Tab 28)
    - Actaea (Box 68, Tab 29)
    - Amsonia (Box 68, Tab 30)
    - Argemone (Box 68, Tab 31)
    - Aristolochia (Box 68, Tab 32)
    - Artemisia (Box 68, Tab 33)
    - Bean stem (Box 68, Tab 34)
    - Beta vulgaris (Box 68, Tab 35)
    - Boehmeria (Box 68, Tab 36)
    - Cabbage (Box 68, Tab 37)
    - Capsella embryo (Box 68, Tab 38)
    - Castanea (Box 68, Tab 39)
    - Citrus (Box 68, Tab 40)
    - Clematis (Box 68, Tab 41)
    - Coleus (Box 68, Tab 42)
    - Convolvulus (Box 68, Tab 43)
    - Cucurbita (Box 68, Tab 44)
    - Cyperus root (Box 69, Tab 1)
    - Delphinium (Box 69, Tab 2)
    - Diospyros endosperm (Box 69, Tab 3)
    - Eobania vermiculata (Box 69, Tab 4)
    - Erigeron (Box 69, Tab 5)
    - Erigonum inflatum (Box 69, Tab 6)
    - Euphorbia (Box 69, Tab 7)
    - Fagus (Box 69, Tab 8)
    - Ficus (Box 69, Tab 9)
    - First reduction division (Box 69, Tab 10)
    - Fraximus (Box 69, Tab 11)
    - Fritillaria (Box 69, Tab 12)
    - Geranium (Box 69, Tab 13)
    - Haplopappus (Box 69, Tab 14)
    - Ipomea (Box 69, Tab 15)
    - Juglans (Box 69, Tab 16)
    - Jussiaea stem (Box 69, Tab 17)
    - Kallstroemia (Box 69, Tab 18)
    - Lemna (Box 69, Tab 19)
    - Lepidodendron (Box 69, Tab 20)
    - Lilium (Box 69, Tab 21)
    - Lily gametophyte (Box 69, Tab 22)
    - Medicago (Box 69, Tab 23)
    - Megaspore mother cell (Box 69, Tab 24)
    - Megagametophyte (Box 69, Tab 25)
    - Megagametogenesis (Box 69, Tab 26)
    - Mentha (Box 69, Tab 27)
    - Metasequoia (Box 69, Tab 28)
    - Microsporogenesis (Box 69, Tab 29)
    - Notholaena (Box 69, Tab 30)
    - Oleander (Box 69, Tab 31)
    - Onion root (Box 69, Tab 32)
    - Pandanus (Box 69, Tab 33)
    - Pelargonium (Box 69, Tab 34)
    - Persimmon endosperm (Box 69, Tab 35)
    - Platanus (Box 69, Tab 36)
    - Pinus (Box 69, Tab 37)
    - Pisum (Box 69, Tab 38)
    - Podophyllum (Box 69, Tab 39)
    - Pseudotsuga (Box 69, Tab 40)
    - Pteris aquilina (Box 69, Tab 41)
    - Quercus (Box 69, Tab 42)
    - Ranunculus (Box 70, Tab 1)
    - Rumex (Box 70, Tab 2)
    - Safflower (Box 70, Tab 3)
    - Sambucus (Box 70, Tab 4)
    - Selagenella (Box 70, Tab 5)
    - Sequoia (Box 70, Tab 6)
    - Sequoioideae (Box 70, Tab 7)
    - Simmondsia (Box 70, Tab 8)
    - Smilax (Box 70, Tab 9)
    - Sphenophyllum (Box 70, Tab 10)
    - Tilia (Box 70, Tab 11)
    - Tribulus (Box 70, Tab 12)
    - Typha (Box 70, Tab 13)
    - Ulmus (Box 70, Tab 14)
    - Unidentified slides (Box 70, Tab 15)
    - Vanilla (Box 70, Tab 16)
    - Vitis (Box 70, Tab 17)
    - Wheat embryo (Box 70, Tab 18)
    - Whitefish mitosis (Box 70, Tab 19)
    - Zea (Box 70, Tab 20)
  - Subseries 4: Plants
    - Acacia (Box 70, Tab 21)
    - Agave (Box 70, Tab 22)
    - Agropyron (Box 70, Tab 23)
    - Allium (Box 70, Tab 24)
    - Amanita (Box 70, Tab 25)
    - Ambrosia (Box 70, Tab 26)
    - Aquilegia (Box 70, Tab 27)
    - Ariocarpus (Box 70, Tab 28)
    - Asclepias (Box 70, Tab 29)
    - Atriplex (Box 70, Tab 30)
    - Auricularia (Box 70, Tab 31)
    - Baccharis (Box 70, Tab 32)
    - Beloperone (Box 70, Tab 33)
    - Beta (Box 70, Tab 34)
    - Bursera (Box 70, Tab 35)
    - Callinadra (Box 70, Tab 36)
    - Canotia (Box 70, Tab 37)
    - Casuarina (Box 70, Tab 38)
    - Cedrus (Box 70, Tab 39)
    - Cereus (Box 70, Tab 40)
    - Chamaerops (Box 71, Tab 1)
    - Cheilanthes (Box 71, Tab 2)
    - Condalia (Box 71, Tab 3)
    - Coryphantha (Box 71, Tab 4)
    - Crassula (Box 71, Tab 5)
    - Cupressus (Box 71, Tab 6)
    - Cycas (Box 71, Tab 7)
    - Dasylirion (Box 71, Tab 8)
    - Datura (Box 71, Tab 9)
    - Delphinium (Box 71, Tab 10)
    - Echinocactus (Box 71, Tab 11)
    - Echinocereus (Box 71, Tab 12)
    - Echinopsis (Box 71, Tab 13)
    - Ephedra (Box 71, Tab 14)
    - Epicampes (Box 71, Tab 15)
    - Equisetum (Box 71, Tab 16)
    - Eriobotrya (Box 71, Tab 17)
    - Erythraea (Box 71, Tab 18)
    - Erythrina (Box 71, Tab 19)
    - Eucalyptus (Box 71, Tab 20)
    - Euphorbia (Box 71, Tab 21)
    - Fouquieria (Box 71, Tab 22)
    - Fraxinus (Box 71, Tab 23)
    - Galpinsia (Box 71, Tab 24)
    - Goodyera (Box 71, Tab 25)
    - Haplophyton (Box 71, Tab 26)
    - Helianthella (Box 71, Tab 27)
    - Hesperocallis (Box 71, Tab 28)
    - Hoffmannseggia (Box 71, Tab 29)
    - Holacantha (Box 71, Tab 30)
    - Hymenoclea (Box 71, Tab 31)
    - Hymenoxys (Box 71, Tab 32)
    - Idria (Box 71, Tab 33)
    - Juniperus (Box 71, Tab 34)
    - Koeberlinia (Box 71, Tab 35)
    - Larrea (Box 71, Tab 36)
    - Lepachys (Box 71, Tab 37)
    - Lycium (Box 71, Tab 38)
    - Malaxis (Box 71, Tab 39)
    - Mammillaria (Box 71, Tab 40)
    - Marsilea (Box 72, Tab 1)
    - Mesembryanthemum (Box 72, Tab 2)
    - Monotropa (Box 72, Tab 3)
    - Morus (Box 72, Tab 4)
    - Muhlenbergia (Box 72, Tab 5)
    - Napolea (Box 72, Tab 6)
    - Nephrolepsis (Box 72, Tab 7)
    - Nolina (Box 72, Tab 8)
    - Notholaena (Box 72, Tab 9)
    - Notocactus (Box 72, Tab 10)
    - Oenothera (Box 72, Tab 11)
    - Olneya (Box 72, Tab 12)
    - Opuntia (Box 72, Tab 13)
    - Papaver (Box 72, Tab 14)
    - Parkinsonia (Box 72, Tab 15)
    - Parosela (Box 72, Tab 16)
    - Pellaea (Box 72, Tab 17)
    - Pinus (Box 72, Tab 18)
    - Pittosporum (Box 72, Tab 19)
    - Pityrogramma Triangularis (Box 72, Tab 20)
    - Platanus (Box 72, Tab 21)
    - Pontentilla (Box 72, Tab 22)
    - Populus (Box 72, Tab 23)
    - Prosopis (Box 72, Tab 24)
    - Psilotum (Box 72, Tab 25)
    - Pteris (Box 72, Tab 26)
    - Quercus (Box 72, Tab 27)
    - Rumex (Box 72, Tab 28)
    - Sabal (Box 72, Tab 29)
    - Scirpus (Box 72, Tab 30)
    - Sebastiana (Box 72, Tab 31)
    - Selaginella (Box 72, Tab 32)
    - Sempervivum (Box 72, Tab 33)
    - Sclerocactus (Box 72, Tab 34)
    - Simmondsia (Box 72, Tab 35)
    - Sophora (Box 72, Tab 36)
    - Spiranthes (Box 72, Tab 37)
    - Sporobolus (Box 72, Tab 38)
    - Stapelia (Box 73, Tab 1)
    - Tamarix (Box 73, Tab 2)
    - Thuja (Box 73, Tab 3)
    - Tillandsia (Box 73, Tab 4)
    - Tidestromia (Box 73, Tab 5)
    - Verbascum (Box 73, Tab 6)
    - Vitis (Box 73, Tab 7)
    - Washingtonia (Box 73, Tab 8)
    - Woodsia (Box 73, Tab 9)
    - Yucca (Box 73, Tab 10)
    - Zamia (Box 73, Tab 11)
  - Subseries 5: Specimens
    - Aristolochia pallida (Box 73, Tab 12)
    - Arum ethiopicum (Box 73, Tab 13)
    - Bantam hybrid sweet corn (Box 73, Tab 14)
    - Erigonum inflantum (Box 73, Tab 15)
    - Grass species (Box 73, Tab 16)
    - Iberus umbellate (Box 74, Tab 1)
    - Ledum palustre (Box 74, Tab 2)
    - Proboscidea (Box 74, Tab 3)
    - Rock layers (Box 74, Tab 4)
    - Sagoutier (Box 74, Tab 5)
    - Spiranthes polyantha (Box 74, Tab 6)
    - Quercus (Box 74, Tab 7)
  - Subseries 6: Various Images
    - 1948- Thermocouple (Box 74, Tab 8)
    - Book drawings by Richard M. Holmes and Wilfred W. Robbins (Box 74, Tab 9)
    - Botany experiments (Box 74, Tab 10)
    - Diagrams (Box 74, Tab 11)
    - Echo I (Box 74, Tab 12)
    - Figures of Introduction to Floral Mechanisms by Samuel Griffith Jones (Box 74, Tab 13)
    - Gerard’s Herbal 1st page (Box 74, Tab 14)
    - Leica copying attachment for lantern slides (Box 74, Tab 15)
    - Leitz Valoy (Box 74, Tab 16)
    - Mandrake (Box 74, Tab 17)
    - Monsato Company add, 1962 (Box 74, Tab 18)
    - Ocular stage micrometer (Box 74, Tab 19)
    - Professors (Box 74, Tab 20)
    - University of Arizona Botany class (Box 74, Tab 21)
- Series VI: Unidentified Photographers
  This series contains photographs and negatives that do not have a designated creator. The series is divided into four subseries organized in alphabetical order.
  - Subseries 1: Agave
    - Agave species unidentified (Box 74, Tab 22)
    - Agave species beginning with A (Box 74, Tab 23)
    - Agave species beginning with B (Box 74, Tab 24)
    - Agave species beginning with C (Box 74, Tab 25)